

# Yulianti Simatupang

**QA Engineer** 

### **About Me**

Software Quality Assurance with a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering and 2-year experience in software testing in manual and automated testing. Extensive experience in software development methodologies including both agile. Process Comprehensive QA technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and attention to detail. I would like to apply my expertise to ensure the Functionality and usability of Software as Quality Assurance. I am also responsible and likes to learn new things.

### **Professional Experience**

### PT ASLI Rancangan Indonesia

Quality Engineer, April 2023 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Create test plans and test cases on Google Sheet
- Identify and analyze the needs of the product being built and meets the acceptance criteria
- Manage the tasks using Clickup development tools
- Create Script for web and API testing with Katalon studio
- Performed API stress testing with Jmeter
- Perform mobile manual testing with Android and iOS on Lookin App
- Create scripts and run mobile automation scripts with Appium

### Bumi Amartha Teknologi Mandiri Klien at Anteraja

Quality Assurance, September 2021 – January 2023 Key responsibilities:

- ey responsibilities:

  Create test plans and test cases using development tools azure
- devops
  Ensure that the product meets the acceptance criteria/ company specifications through BRD (Business Requirement Definition)
- Communicate with product, design, and executive teams through written reports and oral presentations to identify and solve quality issues
- Create script and run web Automation with Katalon Studio tools
- Create manual API testing with Postman to see the response results from the application

#### PT. Javan Cipta Solusi

Quality Engineer Intern, April 2021-August 2021

Key responsibilities:

- Create test cases and discu
- Make sure there are no bugs/issues on the website and the results accordance with the acceptance criteria
- Create task lists and slide task them in ready to test using Taiga development tools
- Automated test scripts are designed and run for web testing. Test scripts are written and executed using Katalon Studio and Playwright Inspector

### CV. KOMPARTO (Komunitas Pariwisata Toba)

Quality Assurance Intern, June 2020 - Desember 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Created detailed and comprehensive test plans and test cases for Tobazone.com web application.
- Created specifications and technical design documents of Tobazone.com web application.

### **My Contact**



( +628-2370-8393-08

Jakarta, Indonesia

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yu lianti-masta-rotuasimatupang-04a1b917a/

### **Technical Skill**

- Software Testing Api, Web and Mobile
- Database: My SQL, SQL-Server, PostgreSQL
- Katalon Studio
- Appium
- Postman
- Jmeter

# **Education Background**

Institut Teknologi Del (Completed in 2021)
Bachelor of Applied Science, Information
Technology

# **Achievements**

#### Program Kreativitas Mahasiswa (PKM) Skema PKMM, 2020

Our team passed to the national stage and got funding for improving our research.

#### Selenium WebDriver Test Automation Framework With Real Project certified Udemy 2021

I learned knowledge related to the use of automation tools with selenium with real projects gmail

#### Belajar Dasar Visualisasi Data dicoding 2020

I learned basic knowledge regarding the use of data visualization